( " THE STORY OF THE LAWSON FAMILY " PLAYS )
( GEAR SHIFTING )
( HORN HONKING )
( WIND HOWLING )
MOTHER : Saint Francis spent many years living alone in the woods .
Then one night , he saw an angel burning in the sky .
And when he woke up ,
he had stigmata .
But loneliness can do strange things to the mind .
Eventually he died of an eye condition
that also would have caused psychosis .
( IN PORTUGUESE )
- ( BRANCH CRACKS ) - Francisca .
( FRANCISCA SPEAKING PORTUGUESE )
MOTHER : Cow eyes are very similar to human eyes .
The construction is almost exactly the same .
The only difference is they 're bigger .
MOTHER : In Portugal ,
we used to practice surgery on cows .
Here , they practice on people .
This is how they kill it .
( SIGHS )
( IN PORTUGUESE )
( BIRDS CHIRPING )
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
( CHUCKLING )
( DISTANT CHATTERING )
( DOOR OPENS )
( DOOR CLOSES )
- Francisca . - Francisca ?
I was just getting to know your daughter .
I 'm Charlie .
Is your husband at home ?
He 'll be home any second now .
But we 're not interested in whatever you 're trying to sell .
I 'm not trying to sell you anything .
May I come inside for a second ?
Just to use the restroom . It 'll only take a second .
You have a lovely home .
Have you lived here a long time ?
The bathroom is through the living room to the right .
Thanks .
Is your husband usually late ?
You said you expected him here any second .
Bathroom is through the living room , to your right .
Would you show me ?
I think you should show me the way .
Ma 'am .
I 'm trying to be polite .
Now , we can try this one more time
before I start to become unreasonable .
I am sorry , sir , but I really need you to leave .
I don 't quite know what you 're planning .
( CHUCKLING )
Hey there , Franny .
I 'm gonna need you to sit over there on that chair and be real quiet .
Can you do that for me ?
( WHISPERS )
Now , why don 't you be a good host
and show me where that bathroom is ?
Well , all right now .
Onwards and upwards .
MAN : ( ON RADIO ) Reporting from the State Fire Marshal 's office today ,
request for all municipal authorities to ban the sale of an imported ragdoll ,
which has been found to be highly flammable .
State Fire Marshal George Chanovec says
every fire department in the state has been contacted about it .
The doll stands 15 inches high ...
The bodies are stuffed with straw ,
and the name A.E. Sutton stamped on the foot .
Fire marshal says the dolls , which sold for less than a dollar
and for usually ...
FATHER : Where 's your mother ?
I couldn 't leave her .
- ( DISTANT POUNDING ) - ( CHARLIE GRUNTING )
( LAUGHING )
( POUNDING CONTINUES )
( BOTH SHUFFLING )
( GLASS SHATTERING )
( RINGING ON TELEVISION )
MAN : ( ON TV ) Why 'd you mark the calendar towards this date ?
WOMAN : ( ON TV ) Look , I want this to happen . I don 't want to see it happen .
MAN : It 'll be over in a few minutes .
WOMAN : I 've got things to do .
MAN : Can 't see the hanging from here .
Just hear it .
WOMAN : Hear it ?
MAN : Yeah , hanging sounds almost as bad as it looks .
( BANGING ON WOOD )
MAN : Trap door bangs open .
FRANCISCA : Do you want something to eat ?
MAN : Probably a few fellows watching will give a ...
- FRANCISCA : Daddy ? - MAN : Hoop or a holler .
( DOOR OPENING ON TV )
( DOOR CLOSING ON TV )
MAN : Trouble ?
BOY : ( ON TV ) I got there too late , they told me .
( FLOOR CREAKING )
( DOOR OPENING )
( MAN SIGHING )
I need help with your mother .
( BOTH PANTING )
( WHEELBARROW CREAKING )
( MAN GRUNTING )
( OWL COOING )
( FATHER SNIFFING )
( FATHER GRUNTING )
- WOMAN : ( ON TV ) Something wrong ? - CHARLIE : Franny ?
MAN : ( ON TV ) No , it 's , uh , I 've never seen a lonesomer town .
CHARLIE : Franny ?
WOMAN : Well , it 's just that ...
CHARLIE : Franny !
MAN : Not everyone . That calendar there says someone 's
been counting the clays .
CHARLIE : Franny !
Franny !
We 'll have to take care of this .
MAN : ( ON TV ) ... for a minute if we could .
CHARLIE : Franny !
MAN : ... that can save our pa and Adam .
Me and Little Joe found Deuce Martin dead .
- CHARLIE : Franny ! - WOMAN : Dead ?
CHARLIE : Franny ! Fran , Fran !
Franny ! Franny ! Franny ! Franny !
( LOUD THUDDING )
( SIGHING )
( CHARLIE BREATHING DEEPLY )
What are you doing ?
FRANCISCA : You needed stitches .
( LAUGHING )
FRANCISCA : Why are you laughing ?
Why us ?
You let me in .
FRANCISCA : You 've done this before .
( GRUNTING )
FRANCISCA : Why do you do it ?
It feels amazing .
You 're gonna kill me , right ?
Why would I kill you ?
You 're my only friend .
I 'm gonna take care of you .
What are you doing ?
( CHAINS RATTLING )
( GURGLING )
MAN : ( ON TV ) Been eating this kind of food all the way from Ohio ?
WOMAN : ( ON TV ) We have , sir .
MAN 2 : ( ON TV ) Well , you keep shoveling it out to him , you 're not gonna have any left .
MAN 3 : ( ON TV ) Where are you headed ?
MAN 2 : We hope to be in Slatersville by week 's end .
Heard word of a large fertile valley there .
And God willing , we hope to buy land and settle in peace .
He won 't make any more noise .
MAN 2 : Yes , and we work for many years put all of our money together .
I love you , Daddy .
MAN 2 : It is our dream to start a fresh new life .
( HEAVY BREATHING )
( SOBBING )
( WATER SPLASHING )
( HEAVY BREATHING )
( CROW CAWING )
( SNORTING )
( MUSIC PLAYING )
( FRANCISCA SPEAKING PORTUGUESE )
( WOMAN SINGING IN PORTUGUESE )
FRANCISCA : Hello .
( COW MOOING )
Hello .
( IN PORTUGUESE )
( SQUEAKING )
( WATER SPLASHING )
( CHARLIE MOANING )
WOMAN : ( ON TV ) Is something wrong ?
MAN : ( ON TV ) Oh , it 's , uh , just that I 've never seen a lonesomer town .
WOMAN : Well , it 's just that everyone 's afraid to watch the Cartwrights die .
MAN : Not everyone . That calendar there says
someone 's been counting the days .
Miss Sally , ma 'am , we 'd like to talk to you for a minute if we could .
You see , you 're the only one left in town now that can save our pa and Adam .
Me and Little Joe found Deuce Martin dead .
WOMAN : ( ON TV ) I told you what I saw at the trial .
- MAN : ( ON TV ) Sally , you lied . - MAN 2 : ( ON TV ) Little Joe , no need for that .
MAN : You were hurting the lady .
MAN 2 : I didn 't mean to hurt you , Sally , I 'm sorry .
I just wanted you to tell the truth , that 's all .
We 're not doing any good here . Let 's go see Barney Ogden .
MAN : Ma 'am .
( IN PORTUGUESE )
( SOBBING )
( DRAWER CREAKING )
( ENGINE STARTING )
( ENGINE REVVING )
( BRAKES SQUEAKING )
( " PSYCHO " PLAYING )
( ENGINE STOPS )
( CAR DOOR OPENING )
( CAR DOOR CLOSING )
So , you live close by ?
A few towns over .
( DOOR OPENING )
( DOOR CLOSING )
KIMIKO : Your house is so neat .
FRANCISCA : Thank you .
Can I get you anything ?
I 'm okay .
Have you lived here a long time ?
My whole life .
Was this your parents ' house ?
Yes .
Do you live here alone now ?
Mm-hmm .
I 'm sorry , I 'm asking so many questions .
I ask a lot of questions when I 'm nervous .
Why are you nervous ?
I don 't do this very often .
Do what ?
Go home with people .
Neither do I.
Okay , so we both have an excuse to be awkward .
Is this your mother ?
Yes .
She 's beautiful .
She was .
What was she like ?
She was a wonderful mother .
What else ?
I don 't know .
Come on . Anything .
What did she do ?
She was a surgeon in Portugal .
What kind ?
Eyes .
When I was little , we used to do the sections together .
I remember I was fascinated by how the inside of the body looked .
She always hoped I would be a surgeon one day .
I dissected a cat once in school .
That sort of stuff always grossed me out .
What happened to her ?
I 'm sorry .
I shouldn 't have asked .
Someone killed her .
What ?
What about your dad ?
I killed him .
No , really .
Really .
What ?
You 're not serious , are you ?
Yeah .
What 's wrong ?
Nothing .
I 'm sorry .
That wasn 't funny .
So sorry .
No , I 'm ... It 's okay . I , um , ( CLEARS THROAT )
I should probably think about heading home soon .
Why ?
Please don 't go .
- I can just call my mom . - No . No .
I 'll drive you home .
No , it 's okay .
- ( BUSY SIGNAL ) - I 'll drive you home .
Please don 't go .
- Please don 't go . - No , no ,
- It 's , um ... it 's okay . - No .
I am ... Listen , I 'm just kind of tired .
I 'm just gonna go .
- Please . - I 'm ... I 'm just gonna ...
- Don 't go . - I 'm gonna go , okay ?
Please , stop .
I 'm just a little tired , okay ?
( THUDDING )
( CHARLIE WHEEZING )
( FOOTSTEPS CREAKING )
( WHEEZING CONTINUES )
( SILVERWARE JANGLES )
( DOOR OPENING )
- ( CHARLIE PANTING ) - ( KNIFE PLUNGING )
( GASPING )
( KNIFE CLINKING )
( HEAVY BREATHING )
( IN PORTUGUESE )
( MUSIC PLAYING )
( WOMAN SINGING IN PORTUGUESE )
( BODY PART THUDDING )
( IN PORTUGUESE )
( SOBBING IN PORTUGUESE )
( BIRDS CHIRPING )
( TRUCK APPROACHING )
( ANTONIO SQUEALING )
( FRANCISCA GIGGLING )
- It 's okay , little guy . - ( CRYING )
He 's just , he 's a little fussy .
It 's okay .
Would you mind putting that back in his mouth ?
( CRYING CONTINUES )
Thank you .
Oh , baby .
Don 't cry .
So , you 're just up this way , right ?
Uh , yes .
Okay .
Have a wonderful afternoon , okay ?
You think I could just hold Antonio ?
I 'm sorry .
We ... We really have to get going .
Please , can I hold him just for a little bit ?
- Okay ? - Okay , okay , just do it quick .
A quick one . Yes , of course .
Of course we can .
Hey , baby .
Come on , little guy .
Yeah , we made a new friend today .
Look at that .
She 's just gonna hold you . Mm-hmm .
Ooh , boo , boo , boo , boo , boo .
It 's okay . It 's okay .
Okay , so you just wanna hold his head up .
Hi , baby .
- Good job . - Hello , baby .
He likes his little ...
his little ...
( IN PORTUGUESE )
What are you ... saying ?
What are you doing ?
No . ( SCREAMING )
No ! Stop ! Please , don 't hurt him , please !
Don 't hurt my baby ! Stop !
Please don 't hurt him !
Please , don 't hurt him , please !
( PANTING )
( FOOTSTEPS POUNDING )
( ANTONIO CRYING )
( GASPING )
( RETCHES )
- ( ANTONIO SCREAMING ) - Hey , baby .
- Don 't scream . - Please don 't do this .
- ( CRYING CONTINUES ) - ( COOING )
- Please give him back to me . - Baby .
- Please get away from him . - Oh .
( MUMBLES IN PORTUGUESE )
( ANTONIO CRYING )
( ANTONIO CRYING CONTINUES )
- ( PANTING ) - ( CRYING CONTINUES )
( GURGLES )
- ( PANTING CONTINUES ) - ( MUMBLING )
( HISSING )
( HUMMING )
( IN PORTUGUESE )
( HISSING )
( HISSING CONTINUES )
( PANTING )
MAN : ( ON TV ) Mr. Loren , I advise you to call this party off now .
The ghosts are already moving and that 's a bad sign .
MR. LOREN : ( ON TV ) Let me apologize for my wife , she 'll join us later .
- What will you have ? - WOMAN : ( ON TV ) Scotch Ann .
- MR. LOREN : Doctor ? - DOCTOR : I 'll have the same .
MR. LOREN : Now , before the party begins , let 's go over the details .
The caretakers will leave at midnight locking us in here
until they come back in the morning .
- Once the door is locked , - ( DOOR OPENING )
- there 's no way out . - ( DOOR SLAMMING )
The windows have bars that a jail would be proud of .
- FRANCISCA : Antonio ? - Now , the only door
- to the outside ... - ( IN PORTUGUESE )
There 's no electricity , no phone .
No one within miles .
So , no way to call for help .
( CRICKETS CHIRPING )
( IN PORTUGUESE )
( FOOTSTEPS )
( CHAINS RATTLING )
( WOMAN HISSING )
It 's only a dream . It 's only a dream .
( PANTING )
( ANTONIO SPEAKING PORTUGUESE )
FRANCISCA : What ?
FRANCISCA : Did you go in the barn ?
( ANTONIO SPEAKING PORTUGUESE )
FRANCISCA : I told you to never go in the barn .
( FRANCISCA SPEAKING PORTUGUESE )
( DOOR SLIDING )
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
( KEYS CLANKING )
( FOOTSTEPS CONTINUING )
( DOOR SLIDING )
( GRUNTING )
( FRANCISCA SCREAMING )
( HORN HONKING )
( FRANCISCA SPEAKING PORTUGUESE )
( IN PORTUGUESE )
Baby ! Baby , wake up .
- Baby . - What 's wrong ?
You know how much I love you , right ?
- What 's wrong ? - Nothing 's wrong , nothing 's wrong .
Whatever you learn , don 't let it change
- how you feel about me , okay ? - ( POUNDING ON DOOR )
- Who 's here ? - POLICEMAN 1 : Open up .
Open up , it 's the police .
- ( SOBBING ) - POLICEMAN 1 : Police !
- ( DOOR BANGING ) - Come on , come on , baby .
Come on . You 're fast . Come on . Come on .
POLICEMAN 1 : Clear ! Get them clear . Backup , upstairs .
( PANTING )
- POLICEMAN 1 : Upstairs . - POLICEMAN 2 : Second floor . Let 's go .
( FOOTSTEPS POUNDING )
- ( DOOR CRASHING ) - ( IN PORTUGUESE )
- POLICEMAN 1 : Up in the air ! - POLICEMAN 2 : Drop the weapon !
POLICEMAN 3 : Hands up !
ANTONIO : Mommy !
( GUNSHOT )
( MUSIC PLAYING )
( WOMAN SINGING IN PORTUGUESE )